taptogo.net 2018-12-06

# Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy describes the collection, use and security of the information obtained from Cardholders of the Transit Access Pass (TAP) program. Defined terms not defined herein are defined in the TAP Cardholder Agreement available.

### Personal Information Collected

A TAP card may either be Balance Protected or not Balance Protected. The TAP Service Center collects a TAP cardholder’s personal information in order to process Personalized Cards and to Balance Protect TAP cards. Examples of personal information include a TAP cardholder’s name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, debit or credit card number and expiration date, or other information that personally identifies a TAP cardholder. The TAP Service Center obtains this personal information from applications and other forms submitted by TAP cardholders to the TAP Service Center by telephone, mail, facsimile transmission or by electronic submission to the TAP website.

### How Personal Information is Used

Personal information will only be used for the purpose of operating and managing the TAP Program. Personal information will not be disclosed to third parties, except (i) as required by law; (ii) as ordered by a court of competent jurisdiction; (iii) where the express written consent of the TAP cardholder has been obtained; (iv) where TAP card utilization activity must be verified to determine the TAP cardholder’s eligibility for continued participation in a special fare program (e.g., employer-sponsored programs); or (v) where shared with an authorized Service Provider for the purpose of creating an integrated transit fare payment system and for the purpose of interoperability with such Service Provider.

### Security

TAP cardholders retain the right to review and edit all of their personal information pertaining to their accounts, whether stored electronically or on paper. Any inquiry or request to obtain a TAP Cardholder’s personal information shall be directed to the TAP Service Center. LACMTA may adopt procedures for review of such information, including but not limited to charging a fee for processing requests for personal information from the TAP Service Center.

### Effective Date

The effective date of this privacy policy is April 1, 2008. It was amended on June 30, 2016.

If LACMTA makes changes to this privacy policy, LACMTA will post the revised policy on the TAP website, www.taptogo.net, including the date of any amendments.
